

# **Sreekanth Vinodkumar**

Nationality: Indian Date of birth: 25/05/1998 Gender: Male

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sreekanth-v-9b0109142/

**Website:** https://sreekanth98.netlify.app/

• Home: Unit 1 - 343 Cameron Ave, N9B1Y8 windsor (Canada)

#### **ABOUT ME**

Looking forward to earning a contract based/part-time/full-time position as a Software developer at an organization where I can apply my technical skills in coding and software design to generate high-end solutions to general software issues along with drawing a better user experience.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Software developer

**Riafy Technologies** [ 26/05/2020 - 08/11/2021 ]

City: Kochi Country: India

Full-stack developer experienced in Node.js and React.js

### Software engineer

**Qburst Technologies** [ 10/11/2021 - 31/07/2022 ]

City: Kochi Country: India

Software engineer with expertise in Python, HTML, CSS, Node.js, React.js.

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

### **Master of Applied Computing specialisation in Artificial Intelligence**

University of Windsor [ 09/2022 - Current ]

Address: Windsor, N9B1Y8 Ontario (Canada)

Website: https://www.uwindsor.ca

#### Bachelor of Technology(Honours) in Computer Science and Engineering

A P J Abdul Kalam Technological University [ 01/08/2016 - 31/07/2020 ]

Address: Mar Athanasius College of Engineering, 686666 Kothamangalam (India)

Website: http://www.mace.ac.in/

Final grade: CGPA - 8.08

# **Higher Secondary Education**

Holy Cross Higher Secondary School [ 01/06/2014 - 31/03/2016 ]

Address: 686584 Kottayam (India)

Final grade: 92.75%

#### **Secondary Education**

**Gayathri Central School** [ 01/06/2013 - 31/03/2014 ]

Address: 686573 Kottayam (India)

Final grade: CGPA - 9.2

#### **PROIECTS**

# Working model of Self-driving Vehicle

[2020]

A self-driving vehicle embedded with a convolutional neural network and shortest path algorithm for predicting the best path and direction which enables safe travel from one location to another.

# TicTacToe puzzle Game Android App

[2020]

Tic-tac-toe is a game for 2 players, X and O, who take turns marking the spaces in a 3×3 grid. The player who succeeds in placing three of their marks in a horizontal, vertical, or diagonal row is the winner. Features include Single player (play with android) with two difficulty levels and Multiplayer

# **Speech Text Converter Android App**

[2020]

An android app for voice to text and text to voice conversion. Build-in TTS engine for text to speech conversion and androids built-in speech recogniser to convert speech into text.

# Life Source - Blood Bank Management System

[2018]

A simple and efficient system for Blood bank management. This system has a real-time geo-powered network of blood donors which allows the hospital to search directly for nearby blood donors thus reducing the middle-man and saving time.

# **Logistics Application**

[ 08/2020 - 12/2020 ]

The goal of this web app is to enable users to check available vehicles to transport logistics from one location to another. When a user requests transportation of goods then the nearest vehicle is allocated to the user. The system also helps to track the vehicle throughout the journey.

#### **Role and Responsibilities:**

- Responsive UI using native CSS and media query.
- Downloading reports and transaction details.
- Google map implementation and tracking of vehicles.
- Implementation of firebase push notification.
- Multi-Language functionality and RTL implementation for corresponding languages.
- Enabled service workers for notifications when the website is not active or closed.

# **Food Delivery System**

[05/2020 - 09/2020]

The scope of the project is to develop a chef and foodie applications, as well as a dashboard for system administrators to manage the system. Foodies can order menus or dishes from a chef instantly or arrange a bulk order for an event. This system also enables the chef to host a food event and invite other chefs and foodies.

# **Role and Responsibilities:**

- Responsive UI using native CSS and media query.
- Implementation of different kinds of charts in the dashboard using ChartJS.
- Implementation of multiple filters and downloading reports in excel format.

# **Online Shopping System**

[04/2021 - 09/2021]

The scope of the project is to develop an application for users to order vegetables and meat, as well as an application for pickers who collect and pack products to make them ready for delivery, and an application for drivers who deliver the product. Apart from these applications, there are consoles to manage the system.

### **Role and Responsibilities:**

- Responsive UI using native CSS and media query.
- Implementation of charts in the console to represent data in an efficient way.
- Implementation of dark and light themes.
- Develop Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Management Information System (MIS), and Logistics Management (LCM) consoles.

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

# **Front End Development**

HTML 5 / CSS / JavaScript / React JS

### **Back End Development**

Node IS

#### **Microsoft Office**

Microsoft Word / Microsoft Excel / Microsoft PowerPoint

#### **Programming Languages**

Python / Java / C Programming / C++

### **Databases**

SQL/MYSQL / PostgresSQL / MongoDB

#### **Tools**

Android Studio / Git

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# **Self-Driving Car using Convolutional Neural Network**

[2020]

Published in International Journal for Research in Applied Science and Engineering Technology (IJRASET) Volume 8, Issue IV, April 2020

#### **HONOURS AND AWARDS**

#### **Project presentation (V-HACK)**

APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University [ 17/02/2019 ]

First prize for Life Source project in University level project presentation.